<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Salt Cellar</title>
    <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Salt Cellar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.rowan.website/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Braindump on Contra Dancing</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-19-braindump-on-contra-dancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-19-braindump-on-contra-dancing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the contra scene since I was born; my parents met at a contra dance, and their main social community is based off of it, so it was kind of unavoidable. I&amp;rsquo;m also a person with a lot of thoughts and opinions, so here are a bunch of them in no particular order.
Dancing and Me I&amp;rsquo;ve been the person driving to every contra dance I could remotely afford1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off-silo blog and social reach</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-07-off-silo-blog-and-social-reach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-07-off-silo-blog-and-social-reach/</guid>
      <description>As expected, when I started writing on a standalone blog instead of long facebook posts, interaction with things I said dropped.
This is frustrating.
I think that I&amp;rsquo;m saying better things than I was in long unedited Facebook posts. I think posts on blog.rowan.website are way more worth reading than any given Facebook post (although there are some that are better, just because I haven&amp;rsquo;t written a blog post on everything I&amp;rsquo;ve written a Facebook post on).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-promotion</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-07-self-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-07-self-promotion/</guid>
      <description>I hate self-promotion. It feels gross, and it feels like I should be letting people come to me, and it feels like a huge imposition on all of my friends.
But there&amp;rsquo;s no way that I&amp;rsquo;m going to be financially successful1 without telling people that I&amp;rsquo;m good at things, and that they should hire me. So I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on it.
It still feels crass. It feels like I&amp;rsquo;m taking advantage of my friends&amp;rsquo; willingness to keep me in their lists, and I always assume that some people I care about have unfollowed my feed on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Morris Ring is Still an Anti-Feminist Institution</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-12-the-morris-ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-12-the-morris-ring/</guid>
      <description>The Morris Ring. An organization that&amp;rsquo;s been irrelevant to any non-morris dancer, largely irrelevant to any side in the United States, and irrelevant to many dancers in the U.K., for a simple reason:
They don&amp;rsquo;t allow women.1 
This comes up again now because of a recent Ring newsletter, containing a motion to, shockingly, allow women dancers.
I&amp;rsquo;ll let y&amp;rsquo;all breathe for a second. I know it&amp;rsquo;s a lot, here in the year of our lord 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the shit is the Shadow DOM, anyway?</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-15-what-the-shit-is-the-shadow-dom-anyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-15-what-the-shit-is-the-shadow-dom-anyway/</guid>
      <description>Shadow DOM: the next frontier in web development.
Or something. Or not.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get y&amp;rsquo;all up to speed. To start with:
What the shit is the DOM anyway? It stands for Document Object Model. It&amp;rsquo;s the result of all of the HTML and Javascript that renders a webpage, and it&amp;rsquo;s what Javascript and CSS interact with.
Yikes. Let&amp;rsquo;s back up a bit.
To start, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a stupidly simple HTML file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we need the Shadow DOM when we have SASS?</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-14-why-do-we-need-the-shadow-dom-when-we-have-sass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-02-14-why-do-we-need-the-shadow-dom-when-we-have-sass/</guid>
      <description>n.b. if you&amp;rsquo;re not a web developer and aren&amp;rsquo;t interested in being one, this post may not be for you. lmk if you want a follow-up that&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain things accessibly!
Ghost dominatrixes? Isn&amp;rsquo;t this a little personal? The Shadow DOM is a concept in web development. It basically lets you make little capsules inside a web page, that have their own separate DOM (Document Object Model).
If that flew over your head: The DOM is, basically, everything in a webpage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>controversial opinions, part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-11-controversial-opinions-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-11-controversial-opinions-part-1/</guid>
      <description>alright. friends.
i&amp;rsquo;ve stayed publicly silent on this great debate for long enough. i can&amp;rsquo;t in good conscience stay silent any longer. i will warn you, though, my views may not match the black and white painting of the issue that you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with.
pineapple on pizza is good whew; that felt good to say.
hawaiian pizza is bullshit relative to other combinations of pineapple and [meat].
pineapple and pepperoni.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>happy christmas!</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-26-happy-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-26-happy-christmas/</guid>
      <description>love, rowan and nicki</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mastodon and coops</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-24-mastodon-and-coops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-24-mastodon-and-coops/</guid>
      <description>or: why social.coop gets it right i write more about my relationship with mastodon here
i am sure i&amp;rsquo;m not the first to write about how there&amp;rsquo;s a direct link between the federated social web and cooperative business ideologies. there&amp;rsquo;s a clear line to be drawn between the idea of a social network run and participated in by the people who own it, with each instance working together to create a bigger and better network, and a business run and participated in etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thoughts on the last jedi</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-27-thoughts-on-the-last-jedi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-27-thoughts-on-the-last-jedi/</guid>
      <description>##or: since when do i cry at star wars movies
(spoilers galore)
 the porgs were a delightful minor detail1. i cried in the first five minutes  corrollary: carrie fisher appears in the first five minutes  i really enjoyed this movie kylo ren: just another shirtless mediocre man  yawn.  i spent like 5 minutes chanting &amp;ldquo;hand! hand! hand!&amp;rdquo; under my breath and miming cutting off and got NOTHING TO SHOW FOR IT  calling it right now: this disappointment was the worst part of the movie  i&amp;rsquo;m unreasonably sad that luke&amp;rsquo;s lightsaber is gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why I join Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-23-why-i-join-mastodon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-23-why-i-join-mastodon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve joined Mastodon four times. The first was in October or November 2016, on mastodon.social, when @shel first joined and told all of her friends; I stuck around for a bit, but only had two or so friends on it (@shel and @ebeth), and I had a large social group on Twitter, so i went back to &amp;lsquo;birdsite&amp;rsquo; (Twitter, per bits of the fediverse).
now I&amp;rsquo;m back. a couple of months ago, I picked @rowanlupton@mastodon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why pylodon exists</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-24-why-pylodon-exists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2017-12-24-why-pylodon-exists/</guid>
      <description>first off: mastodon is amazing and i&amp;rsquo;m so impressed by @gargon&amp;rsquo;s tenacity and brilliance in bringing it to life
that being said, the biggest weakness that i see with mastodon is how intertwined the frontend and backend are. it has what i understand to be an excellent API, but i wanted to be able to fire up a mastodon server and write my own frontend, without mastodon&amp;rsquo;s one taking up space and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>yet another explanation of Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-08-yet-another-explanation-of-mastodon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-08-yet-another-explanation-of-mastodon/</guid>
      <description>The situation: you&amp;rsquo;ve seen people talking about Mastodon. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re intrigued, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re not. Either way, when they&amp;rsquo;ve tried to explain it to you, you&amp;rsquo;ve been confused, turned off, or maybe even a little angry that they won&amp;rsquo;t shut up about it.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and undo some of that damage. This post is intended to start out with a non-technical general explanation and go from there to explain Mastodon in more and more detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>youth trad song weekend 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-08-youth-trad-song-weekend-2k18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-08-youth-trad-song-weekend-2k18/</guid>
      <description>another yts, come and gone.
i remember at the first couple of yts weekends, i went to workshops and led songs and generally participated a ton. contrast to the past couple of years, when i&amp;rsquo;ve mostly done sound, played games, sang some daily book, and joined in a song circle or two.
i&amp;rsquo;m of two minds about all of this. am i wasting my money, and taking a space that somebody else could have, who would more fully enjoy the programming of the weekend?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>yts 2k18 - sound</title>
      <link>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-08-yts-2k18-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.rowan.website/posts/2018-01-08-yts-2k18-sound/</guid>
      <description>jesus fuckin christ y&amp;rsquo;all i was so stressed on friday
important note: i don&amp;rsquo;t wish to cast any blame or aspersions on the yts committee. they do a fantastic job running a huge weekend, everything worked out, and everybody had a great time.
months before yts, the committee and i were in touch about sound, compensation, etc. i mentioned in an email about this that i&amp;rsquo;d be happy to provide sound equipment, and nothing more was said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>